Guide to the Pacific Improvement Company Records, 1901-1966 JL017
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Crocker-Huffman Co. General File, 1917 - 1919.
  - “Crocker-Huffman Land & Water Co. - Monthly Statistics ”., 1915-1919 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - “Crocker-Huffman Land & Water Co. - Index to Correspondence ”. Files A-Z by name or respondent., 1917-1920 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - L.D. Ven Horne, ”. Correspondence between Van Horne and Morse re: projects in Merced. Copies of job orders sent to Morse, Feb. 1918 - April 1919 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Correspondence Accompanying Checks, ”. C-H Co. checks sent by E.M. Brown, office manager, to Morse, in S.F., to be signed, and then returned., March - Dec. 1919 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. Correspondence Accompanying Checks, ”. Contents similar to 52-4., August 1918 - Feb. 1919 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. Correspondence Accompanying Checks, ”. Similar to 52-4., Jan. - July 1918 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. Miscellaneous Correspondence ”. Predominantly letters between Morse and Van Horne or Brown re: sundry fairly unimportant issues., 1919 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. Miscellaneous Correspondence 1918”. Contents similar to, 52-7. (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Donations and Subscriptions ”., March 1918 - May 1919 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Maps and Surveys ”. Concerning various C-H Co. lands., Feb. - June 1918 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. Merced Irrigation District ”. M.I.D. not actually formed until late 1919 after the passage of Calif. Senate Bill 493 (Irrigation Bill). Most of correspondence re: helping bill to be passed and proposed M.I.D., Jan. 1918 to Nov. 1919 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Livestock and Meat Packing ”., Nov. 1918 to Dec. 1919 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Livestock and Meat Packing, ”., Jan. - Oct. 1918 (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Personnel, ”. Predominantly Morse's referrals and recommendations of young men to Van Horne for work at C-H Co., Jan. 1918 to Jan 1920 (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Real Estate Trade - Bert Crane Deal, ”. Crane will trade 4 1/2 sections of his land for China Cabin Field. Also quick mention of Deane Field., May 1918 to Dec. 1919 (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Legal Buits and Accounts, ”. Correspondence only., Jan. 1918 - Sept. 1919 (Box 52, Folder 16)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Dry Creek Property ”. Reservoir and range land owned by C-H Co., March 1918 - March 1919 (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Cressey Colony, ”. Re: rights-of-way, other documents, sales., 1919 (Box 52, Folder 18)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Cressey Colony, 1918”. Similar to, 52-18. (Box 52, Folder 19)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Water System, ”. Re: royalties, rights, up keep of system, rates, accounts, plans to increase business., April 1918 to Aug. 1919 (Box 52, Folder 20)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Ward Ranch, March 1918 to Dec. 1919”. Ranch near Cressey owned by C-H Co. Plan to sell it to Harry Morse (Samuel's brother) in (Box 52, Folder 21)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Jordan Atwater Tract ”., April - June 1918 (Box 52, Folder 22)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Yamato Colony, ”. Correspondence re: sales and contracts for deeds., Jan. 1918 to Oct. 1919 (Box 52, Folder 23)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Merced River Tract, ”. Correspondence re: deeds from C-H Co. to Universal Land Co., March 1918 to Nov. 1919 (Box 52, Folder 24)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Merced Colonies #2 and # ”., 3, Feb. 1918 to Dec. 1919 (Box 52, Folder 25)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Dean Fields and El Capitan Colony, ”. Up for sale., August 1916 to Dec. 1919 (Box 52, Folder 26)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co.-Canal System, ”., Dec. 1917 - June 1919 (Box 52, Folder 27)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Insurance and Bonds, ”., May 1918 to August 1919 (Box 52, Folder 28)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Deeds and Contracts to Various C-H Co. Lands, ”., Dec. 1917 - Dec. 1919 (Box 52, Folder 29)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Railroad Commission Correspondence, ”. Re: certain complaints against C-H Co. and the question of R.R. Commission jurisdiction over C-H Co., May 1918 (Box 52, Folder 30)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Morse to Henry Hall ”. Re: lost Geary St., Park and Ocean R.R. that Hall, employee of C-H Co., had looked up., 6/23/19 (Box 52, Folder 31)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Crocker Colony and Bradley Colony Sale to J.B. Hart, ”., Aug. 1918 to Sept. 1919 (Box 52, Folder 32)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Crocker Estate Correspondence re: Property, ”., Jan. - June 1917 (Box 52, Folder 33)
- Correspondence - A.D. Shepard, General Manager of P.I. Co., Open files by numbers 1-100., March - May 1909.
  - “Shepard - Warner re: Physical Plant, ”. A.D. Shepard was General Manager of P.I. Co; and H.H. Warner was the Manager of the Hotel., 3/1-5/29, 1909 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - “Del Monte Hotel Plant Improvements, ”. Shepard corresponds re: building an ice plant and adding a sun porch at the hotel., 3/3/09-4/28/09 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - “Del Monte Hotel Personnel, ”. Letters to and from Shepard. Requests and offers for jobs at the hotel., 3/7/09-5/26/09 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - “Shepard - Warner re: Reservations and letter of introduction ”., 3/2/09-5/29/09 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - “Shepard - Warner Re: Reservations and Letters of Introduction ”. Reports of accounts payable and receivable. Monthly reports of guests., 3/4/09-5/30/09 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - “Shepard - Warner Re: Hotel Requisitions, ”. Orders for all kinds of material from P.I. Co. ie. poles, foodstuff, electrical equipment., 3/19/09-5/22/09 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - “Shepard - Warner - Southern Pacific Co., ”. Correspondence with S.P. Co. officials re: train service L.A. to Del Monte., 3/31/09-5/30/09 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - “Del Monte Hotel Publicity and Advertising, ”., 3/1/09-5/31/09 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - “Roads around and to the Hotel, ”. Correspondence re: the conditions of and improvement work on roads., 3/4/09-5/5/09 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - “Water and Electricity - Bills and Estimates ”., 3/3/09-4/11/09 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - “Del Monte Hotel Cars and Horses, ”. Inquiries from prospective customers, and correspondence accompanying bills., 3/9/09-5/30/09 (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - “Del Monte Art Gallery, ”., 3/1/09-5/26/09 (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - “Conventions at the Hotel ”., 3/1/09-5/31/09 (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - “Letter from Warner to J.K. Steels re: Wither's Tract, ”., March - April 1909 (Box 53, Folder 14)
  - “A.D. Shepard - Miscellaneous Correspondence ”., 3/1/09-5/28/09 (Box 53, Folder 15)
  - “Pacific Grove Academy, ”. School for boys, students boarded in the Pacific Grove Hotel., May 1909 (Box 53, Folder 16)
  - “Gas Costs at Pacific Grove Hotel, ”., April - May 1909 (Box 53, Folder 17)
  - “Nichols - Pacific Grove Hotel Employee, ”. Man with tuberculosis is let go. Correspondence between Shepard, Cordy (Hotel Manager) and doctor., April 1909 (Box 53, Folder 18)
  - “Letter of Introduction for W.H. Morgan ”. From Shepard to Cordy., 5/7/09 (Box 53, Folder 19)
  - “Advertising and Lectures Promoting Monterey Peninsula ”., 3/18-5/24, 1909 (Box 53, Folder 20)
  - “Monterey Peninsula Road Construction and Improvement, ”., 3/1/09-5/26/09 (Box 53, Folder 21)
  - “Pebble Beach Lodge and Clubhouse, ”., 3/1/09-5/30/09 (Box 53, Folder 22)
  - “Del Monte - Miscellaneous, ”., 3/1/09-5/30/09 (Box 53, Folder 23)
  - “Trackless Trolley Cars ”. Correspondence with manufacturers, re: consideration of installing a trolley on Monterey Peninsula., 3/2/09-5/20/09 (Box 53, Folder 24)
  - “Monterey County Water Works, ”., 3/1/09-5/29/09 (Box 53, Folder 25)
  - “Water Rights on the Carmel River, ”., 3/3/09-5/28/09 (Box 53, Folder 26)
  - “Electric Autos and Trackless Trolleys, ”., 3/1/09-5/31/09 (Box 53, Folder 27)
  - “Shepard to D.B. Hodgson, Gen. Mgr. of Guatemala Central R.R. ”., 3/8/09-5/21/09 (Box 53, Folder 28)
  - “Electric Autos, Trackless Trolleys and Guatemala Central R.R. ”. Trade circulars and brochures re: autos and trolleys. Correspondence with officials (mostly Hodgson) of G.C.R.R., 3/1/09-5/28/09 (Box 53, Folder 29)
  - “Job Applications for Positions at Various P.I. Co. Subsidiaries ”., 3/1/09-5/28/09 (Box 53, Folder 30)
  - “Rancho Del Monte - Laureless Ranch ”., 3/5/09-5/28/09 (Box 53, Folder 31)
  - “Geary St., Park and Ocean R.R. Co. Correspondence ”., 3/1/09-5/29/09 (Box 53, Folder 32)
  - “Correspondence and Reports re: Free Tram Transportation ”., 3/4/09-5/28/09 (Box 53, Folder 33)
  - “Sand Business Billing and Correspondence ”, 3/2/09-5/28/09 (Box 53, Folder 34)
  - “Thomas H. Hubbard, ”. Three letters re: P.I. Co. financial policy and plans., Jan. - March 1908 (Box 53, Folder 35)
  - “Correspondence Between Hubbard and Shepard re: Northern Electric R.R. Co., ”., March 1909 (Box 53, Folder 36)
  - “Correspondence Accompanying and Explaining P.I. Co. Financial Reports ”., March - May 1909 (Box 53, Folder 37)
  - “Correspondence Accompanying Deeds, ”. P.I. Co. to Mssrs. Mitchael and Bischof., March - May 1909 (Box 53, Folder 38)
  - “Hope Ranch, ”., 3/1/09-5/29/09 (Box 53, Folder 39)
  - “.S.F. Real Estate - Illinois St. ”., 3/2/09-5/10/09 (Box 53, Folder 40)
  - “Announcements of Weekly P.I. Co. Directors' Mettings ”., 3/1/09-5/24/09 (Box 53, Folder 41)
  - “Hope Ranch Book ”. Publicity and Advertising Brochure., 3/1/09-5/10/09 (Box 53, Folder 42)
  - “Castle Crag ”., 3/1/09-5/29/09 (Box 53, Folder 43)
  - “Re: Testimony of Shepard and Platt Before N.Y. Judge ”., 3/19/09-4/10/09 (Box 53, Folder 44)
  - “To Southern Pacific Co. - Overcharge Claims ”., 3/4/09-5/29/09 (Box 53, Folder 45)
  - “Pacific Telephone and Telegraph Co: ”., 3/18/09-5/24/09 (Box 53, Folder 46)
  - “Southern Pacific Co. - Shipping Rates ”., 12/1/08-5/28/09 (Box 53, Folder 47)
  - “Briquetting Coal - Ione Iron & Coal Co. ”., 3/16/09-5/24/09 (Box 53, Folder 48)
  - “Beaver Hill Coal ”., 3/4/09-5/28/09 (Box 53, Folder 49)
  - “Ione Iron and Coal Co. ”. Correspondence and reports., 3/1/09-5/30/09 (Box 53, Folder 50)
  - “Board of State Harbor Commissioners, ”., 1/11/09-5/7/09 (Box 53, Folder 51)
  - “Pacific Grove Hotel re: Financial Reports ”., 3/5/09-5/31/09 (Box 53, Folder 52)
  - “Abstract of Title made by Wright Abstract Co. Inc., Santa Barbara”. Abstract of title to Lot #4, outside Pueblo Lands, City of Santa Barbara., Feb. 10, 1919. (Box 54)
  - “Supplemental Abstracts of Estates of Thomas Hope and David Beebe”. Both deceased. Made by Wright Abstract Co.”. (Box 55)
  - “Ontare Ranch Abstract of Title, Volume”. Made by Wright Abstract Co. ”., 2/10/19 (Box 56)
  - “Ontare Ranch Abstract of Title, Volume II”. Made by Wright Abstract Co. Includes maps., 2/10/19. (Box 57)
  - “Hope Ranch Abstract, Volume II”. Made by Wright Abstract Co., 2/10/19. (Box 58)
  - “Hope Ranch Abstract, Volume II”. Made by Wright Abstract Co., 2/10/19. (Box 59)
  - “Abstract of Title to the Hope Ranch”. Made by Wright Abstract Co., original but continuation, dated: June 22, 1909 dated: 1915. (Box 60)
  - “Abstract of Title to Part of Rancho Las Positas y La Calera”. Showing particularly the interest of John T. Hope in said Rancho. Made by C.A. Thompson attny. and searcher of records, Santa Barbara., Dated: 10/14, 1687. (Box 61)
  - “Laguna Blanca Water Co. Abstract, Volume I”. Made by Wright Abstract Co., 2/10/19. (Box 62)
  - “Laguna Blanca Water Co. Abstract, Volume III”. Made by Wright Abstract Co., 2/10/19. (Box 63)
  - “An Abstract of Title to Property Owned by William Sloane”. At the southeast corner of Bute and Duke Streets, Norfolk, Va. Examination completed by Clair E. Crawford., 10/1/25 (Box 64)
  - “Abstract of Title of Arroyo Seco Rancho, Amador County, Calif., Volume I”. Made by M.E. Fortenrose, Searcher of Records, Jackson, Calif., 3/23/17. (Box 65)
  - “Abstract of Title of Arroyo Seco Rancho, Volume II”. Made by M.E. Fortenrose, 3/23/17. (Box 66)
  - “Abstract of Title and List of Incumbrances”. Of town of El Verano and subdivisions of adjoining property. Made by Sonoma County Abstract Bureau, Santa Rosa, 3/15/13. (Box 67)
  - “Abstract of Title and List of Incumbrances”. Town of El Verano and remaining interest of P.I. Co., El Verano Improvement Assn., El Verano Villa Assn. in Petaluma Rancho. Made by Sonoma County Abstract Bureau., 6/28/10. (Box 68)
  - “Town of El Verano, Villa Association, Improvement Association”. Contains the conveyances of property in parts of El Verano, in condensed form. (Box 69)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal Co. - Amended By-Laws, Adopted ”., Jan. 4, 1907 (Box 70)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal Co. Minute Book, Dec. 18, 1906 - Aug. 11, 1937”. (Box 71)
  - “Geary St. Park & Ocean R.R. Co. Minutes”., March 22, 1906 March 28, 1913. (Box 72)
  - “Oak Creak Land & Water Co.”. Minutes ”. Almost entirely empty and blank., 12/14/07 and 8/3/09 (Box 73)
  - “Ledger”. Oakland Water Front Co. Inc., 1906 - 1919. (Box 74)
  - “Hotel Del Monte - Guest Record ”. Record of number of adults, children and nurses in the hotel on every day in that period., 1/1/07-2/6/18 (Box 75)
  - “P.I. Co. Credit Book”. Lists name of person or corporation, address, debit and credit., Dates range: 1907 - 1909. (Box 76)
  - “By-Laws of the Pacific Coast Commercial Company, Inc.”. (Box 77)
  - “Minutes of Pacific Coast Commercial Co., Inc.”. Includes proxies and notices., 8/4/13 - 11/9/33. (Box 78)
  - “Pacific Coast Commercial Co. - Stock Certificate Register”. Transfers - Almost blank., 1913. (Box 79)
  - “Pacific Coast Commercial Co. - Stock Journal and Ledger”. entries. Mostly blank., 1913 - (Box 80)
  - “Pacific Coast Commercial Co. - Stock Certificate Book”. Filled with cancelled and blank certificates. Issued, 1913 - 1919. (Box 81)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal Co. - Stock Certificate Book (Old)”. Cancelled and blank certificates, issued, 1910 - 1922. (Box 82)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal Co. - Stock Certificate Book”. (New), blank certificates and stubs of issued certificates, 12/6/23. (Box 83)
  - “Reports on the Value of the Preperty of the Monterey County Water Works”. Monterey, Calif., made by Hunter and Hudson, Consulting Engineers, S.F. Vol. I., 1/29/14. (Box 84)
  - “Report on Value M.C.W.W. Property”. Vol. II., 1/29/14. (Box 85)
  - “Report on Value M.C.W.W. Property”. Vol. III., 1/29/14. (Box 86)
  - “Report on Value M.C.W.W. Property Vol. IV., 1/29/14. (Box 87)
  - “Minute Book #3 of the Pacific Improvement Company”., July 26, 1916 - April 9, 1919. (Box 88)
  - “Minute Book #4 of the Pacific Improvement Company”., April 24, 1919 - Dec. 19, 1923. (Box 89)
  - “Minute Book #6 of the Pacific Improvement Company”., July 27, 1929 - 1968. (Box 90)
  - “Pacific Improvement Co. - Stock Certificates Book”. Blank and cancelled certificates. Issued Nos. 49-148 (old)., 1909 - 1923. (Box 91)
  - “Pacific Improvement Co. - Stock Certificates Book.”. Issued Nos. 1-50 (new)., 9/4/29. (Box 92)
  - “Pacific Improvement Co. - Monthly Reports Jan. - Oct. 1917, Balance Sheets Vol. I of Annual Report, Profit & Loss Statements, Vol. II of Annual Report (Box 93)
  - “Pacific Improvement Co. - Monthly Reports Annual Report 1919”., Jan. - Oct. 1919 (Box 94)
  - “Pacific Improvement Co. - Monthly Reports Annual Report 1920”., Jan. - Oct. 1920 (Box 95)
  - “Pacific Improvement Co. - Monthly Reports for Annual Report 1921”. (Box 96)
  - “Pacific Improvement Co. - Monthly Reports for Annual Report 1923”. (Box 97)
  - “Pacific Improvement Co. - Monthly Reports for Annual Report 1924”. (Box 98)
  - “Ledger #1 Pacific Improvement Co.”. inc., with index., 6/1,1883 to 12/31/1888 (Box 99)
  - “Ledger #2 Pacific Improvement Co.”. mostly blank., 1889 - (Box 100)
  - “Journal #1 Pacific Improvement Co.”. inc., 6/1/1883 to 12/6/1889 (Box 101)
  - “Journal A Pacific Improvement Co”. inc., 1/2/1890 to 12/30/1893 (Box 102)
  - “Ledger A Pacific Improvement Co.”. Entries, 1890 - 1891. (Box 103)
  - “Pacific Improvement Co. Journal”., 3/1906 - 11/1911. (Box 104)
- Box containing California State Legislative and Judicial Business in soft bound volumes.
  - “California Legislature, Fifty-third Session Final Calendar of Legislative Business”. History and index of all Senate and Assembly bills, constitutional amendments, concurrent and joint resolutions introduced. Lists of officers, members attachï¿½s and standing committees of the Senate and Assembly., 1939. (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - “Legislative Digest inclusive”. Bills, constitutional amendaments - introduced prior to Constitutional Recess, California Legislature, Fifty-third Session., 1939, January 2 to January 25 (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - “California Legislature Fifty-third Session, 1939. Senate and Assembly Semi-Final History”. Showing action on all bills, constitutional amendments, joint and concurrent resolutions to and including the day of adjournment for the constitutional recess, Jan. 25, 1939. (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - “California Legislature Fifty-second Session, 1937. Senate and Assembly Semi-Final History”. Showing all action up to Constitutional Recess from, Jan. 25, 1937. (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - “Legislative Digest and Subject List of Bills, Constitutional Amendments and Resolutions introduced prior to the Constitutional Recess as of California Legislature Fifty-second Session 1937., Jan. 22, 1937 (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - “Final Report of the Fact Finding Committee to the Senate”. California Legislature Fiftieth Session Containing all partial reports., 1933 - (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - “Legislative Digest 1933”. Digest of Bills and Constitutional Amendments introduced prior to Constitutional Recess as of California Legislature, Fiftieth Session., Jan. 28, 1933. (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - “California Legislature - Fiftieth Session 1933 Senate and assembly Semi-Final History”. Showing action on all Bills, Constitutional Amendments, Joint and Concurrent Resolutions up to Constitutional Recess, Jan. 28, 1933. (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - “Second Biennial Message of Governor C.C. Young to the Legislature of the State of California, ”., 1931 (Box 105, Folder 9)
  - “Legislative Digest Digest of Bills and Constitutional Amendments introduced prior to the Constitutional Recess”. California Legislature Forty-ninth Session., 1931 (Box 105, Folder 10)
  - “Final Report of the California Tax Commission”. Submitted to the Governor of California, March 5, 1929”. (Box 105, Folder 11)
  - “First Biennial Message of Governor C.C. Young to the Legislature of the State of California, 1929”. (Box 105, Folder 12)
  - “California Legislature Forty-eight Session, Final Calendar of Legislature Business”., 1929 (Box 105, Folder 13)
  - “In the Supreme Court of the State of California, Estelle and Charles Christin Edward v. Clark et al, ”. Transcript of Appeal from Superior Court in S.F., Appellant's opening brief, points and authorities on behalf of Respondent, Appellant's reply brief., July, 1916 (Box 105, Folder 14)
  - “The Gold Standard and the Administrations General Economic Program”. Reprinted from Chase Economic Bulletin, Vol. XIII, No. 1 and “Some Fallacies Underlying the Demand for `Inflation' ”, reprinted from Chase Economic Bulletin, Vol. XIII, No. 2. Both by Benjamin M. Anderson, Jr., Ph.D., Economist of the Chase Manhattan Bank. Both published on, May 1933. (Box 105, Folder 15)
  - “Regulations No. 31 - U.S.I.R.S. - Laws and Regulations relative to Excise Tax on Corporations, Joint Stock Companies, Associations and Insurance Companies, ”., Dec. 3, 1909 (Box 105, Folder 16)
  - “73rd Congress, 1st Session, Senate Document No. 43: Contracts Payable in Gold, an article by George Cyrus Thorpe, Showing the legal effect of agreements to pay in Gold. U.S. Government Printing Office ”., 1933 (Box 105, Folder 17)
  - “In the U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit: Clara and Otis Wright and Gertrude and T.T.C. Gregory v. Washoe County Bank et al. Appellant's Brief”. A.C. Van Fleet, attorney for Appellants, 1909. (Box 105, Folder 18)
  - “U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals for Ninth Circuit. Wrights and Gregorys v. Washoe County Bank et al”. Transcript of record, upon appeal from the U.S. District Court for District of Nevada. (Box 105, Folder 19)
  - “In the Supreme Court of the State of California: John J. Lineham v. John Doe Devincense”. Transcript of Appeal from the order of the Superior Court of the State of California, in and for the County of San Mateo granting defendents motion for a new trial, Appellant's opening brief, brief for Respondent, Appellant's closing brief. A.C. Van Fleet, Attny., March 1913 (Box 105, Folder 20)
  - “In the District Court of Appeal, State of California, First Appellate District: W.A. Brown v. J.J. Dwyer, George M. Hill, Thomas S. Williams - Board of State Harbor Commissioners: Transcript of Appeal from Superior Court in S.F., Appellant's opening brief, Respondent's reply brief, Appellant's closing brief”. A.C. Van Fleet - Attny. For Appellant., Dec. 1913. (Box 105, Folder 21)
  - “In the District Court of Appeal, State of California, First Appellate District: Henry Cowell Lime & Cement Co. v. Fred H. Figel: Transcript of Appeal from Superior Court in Santa Clara, Appellant's Opening Brief, Re-spondent's Brief, Appellant's Closing Brief, Respondent' Oral Argument.”., April 1914. (Box 105, Folder 22)
  - “In the Supreme Court of the State of California - William T. Grosse v. C.R. Peterson and Pioneer Soap Co. Transcript of Appeal from Superior Court in S.F., Appellant's Opening Brief, Brief for Respondent, Appellant's Reply Brief”. A.C. Van Fleet - attny. for appellant., June 1914. (Box 105, Folder 23)
  - “California Election Laws, ”. Very small handbook., 1932 (Box 105, Folder 24)
- Record Box containing various hard and soft bound volumes: geological surveys, real estate etc.
  - “Washington Geological Survey - Bulletin No. 10: The Goal Fields of Pierce County by Joseph Daniels”. soft bound., 1914 - (Box 106, Folder 1)
  - “Washington Geological Survey - Bulletin No. 10: The Coal Fields of Pierce County”. Hard bound with many illustrations and photographs., 1914 (Box 106, Folder 2)
  - “Mineral Resources of the Pacific States and Territories West of the Rockies - J.R. Browne”. Published by H.H. Bancroft & Co., 1868. (Box 106, Folder 3)
  - “Report of the California State Board of Equalization for ”. Including special reports to the Legislature concerning comparative tax burdens and utility valuations., 1929-1930 (Box 106, Folder 4)
- File containing: “Pamphlets re: Municipal Zoning and Zoning Laws”. Three pamphlets. (Box 106, Folder 5)
- File containing: “Pamphlets, Reports and Brochures re: Real Estate, Taxes and Investment”. Among other contents: Arizona Corp. Laws and the Advantages of Incorporating in Arizona, Respective Positions of the ten Calif. Building and Loan Associations, Statements of Assets and Liabilities - Monterey Office. Del Monte Properties Co., and Analysis of Final Report of Calif. State Tax Commission., Oct. 10, 1929 - (Box 106, Folder 6)
  - “Kern County, California. Guide for the Subdivision of Land, Kern County Planning Commission ”., 1930 (Box 106, Folder 7)
  - “The Property Brief as an Aid in Selling”. Nat'l. Assn. of Real Estate Boards, 1931. (Box 106, Folder 8)
  - “County of Los Angeles Regional Plan of Highways - Section 4 Long Beach - Rendondo Area ”., 1931 (Box 106, Folder 9)
  - “California Blue Book ”. Also called State Roster, 1932 (Box 106, Folder 10)
  - “Summary Report of California Tax Research Bureau”. In Office of State Board of Equalization submitted to the People and the Legislature of Calif., Dec. 1, 1932. (Box 106, Folder 11)
  - “The Tax Digest”. Volume 12, Number 11, Nov. 1934. (Box 106, Folder 12)
  - “The Tax Digest”. Volume 12, Number 12, Dec. 1934. (Box 106, Folder 13)
  - “Planning for the Future of American Cities”. American Society of Planning Officials., 1935 (Box 106, Folder 14)
  - “Planning for City, State, Region and Nation”. American Society of Planning Officials., 1936 (Box 106, Folder 15)